Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. Why the Lord thy God am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquities
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousand of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold you on guilt that
take of his name in vain. Remember the
Sabbath day to keep it holy.
Six days shall thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work. Thou, nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in the
midst, and rested the seventh day, when
for the Lord blessed the Sabbath day,
and hallowed it. Honor thy father and
thy mother, that thy days may be long
upon the land which the Lord thy God
giveth thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou
shall not commit adultery. Thou shall
not steal. Thou shall not bear false
witness against thy neighbor. Thou shall
not cover thy neighbor's house. Thou not
cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his man's
servant, nor his maid servant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. We read Exodus 21-17.
And may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We're here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream. So,
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
question maximum, two scripture maximum.
But let me introduce to you the family
that's on the panel this evening. Got
brother Jerome.
>> Rest in peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Tanzel.
>> Good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Sean.
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. And sister
Deborah. Before we begin the session,
we'd like to remind everybody that we
are in our Black History lesson and we
will be doing this Saturday at 12 noon
part four, the priest of God. The priest
of God. You don't want to miss out on
that. So, with that being said, Sister
Deborah, what is our first question of
the evening?
>> Uh, yes. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Be alert as in second Timothy 3:8.
Is there any other references to Janice
and Jan Breeze? Why did Paul reference
them from the Old Testament?
>> All right. So that's second Timothy 3
and8 talking about Janies and Jambre. So
brother Julius
let's go there brother Tenzel let's go
to second Timothy 3.
But what we going to do we going to pick
it up at verse 5
and then we going to skip to seven when
you get it. 2 Timothy 3 and verse 5.
having a form of godliness, but denying
the power thereof, from such turn away.
>> Verse seven,
>> ever learning and never able to come to
the knowledge of the truth.
>> Ever learning and never able to come to
the knowledge of the truth. So if
Janison Jambre is mentioned here by name
to show you that thing that happened in
that's happening today or will happen
today has happened in the past. Now
verse eight, go ahead.
>> Now as Jazz and Jamres with withtood
Moses, so do these also resist the
truth. Manist
>> they resist the what?
>> The truth
>> because the book says in verse seven,
ever learning and never able to come to
the knowledge of the truth. People don't
like truth. Go ahead and ver continue at
verse eight. Men of corrupt minds
reprobate concerning the faith.
>> Continue at verse n.
>> But they shall proceed no further.
>> Their body shall be manifest unto all
men as theirs also was.
>> So the truth will always eat up a lie.
Let's go to Exodus the 34 uh Exodus the
7th chapters.
Exodus chapter 7.
Now it named them in 2 Timothy 3 and 8.
It named the two sorcerer magicians.
Now
Exodus 7 and pick it up at verse 7. Go
ahead.
>> And Moses was four score years old and
Aaron four score and three years old
when they spake unto Pharaoh.
>> Uhhuh. And the Lord spake unto Moses and
unto Aaron, saying, Now when Pharaoh
shall speak unto you, saying, Show a
miracle for you, then thou shall say
unto Aaron, take that rod and cast it
before Pharaoh, and it shall become a
serpent.
>> Now before Pharaoh, now we talking about
in the days of Moses,
>> but look at the men that withtood. But
continue to read.
>> And Moses and Aaron went in unto
Pharaoh, and they did so as the Lord had
commanded. And Aaron cast down his rod
before Pharaoh and before his servants,
and it became a serpent.
>> Go ahead.
>> Then Pharaoh also called the wise men
and the sorcerers.
>> The wise men and the sorcerers, Janice
and Jambre, the good sorcerers. Go
ahead.
>> Now the magicians of Egypt, they also
did in like manner with their with their
enchantments.
For they cast down every man his rod.
They became serpents. But Aaron's rods
swallowed up their rods.
>> So now they stuff was fake and
influenced by the power of Satan, the
devil. But
Moses were operating in the power of
God. His rod ate up their snakes. Ate up
ate up theirs. For what reason? Verse
back to verse five and we're done.
And the Egyptians shall know that I am
the Lord. When I stretch forth my hand
upon Egypt and bring out the children of
Israel from among them
>> and because they could not do what Moses
serpent did, all this stuff was done was
fake. But in the last days, Paul is
referring to Janice and Jambre because
these people going to have uh uh working
the the man of sin is going to operate
uh under the power of Satan and we could
be a be able to call cause fire to come
down from heaven and he going to be able
to do the same thing. But the word of
God is going to be triumphant. So that's
why he referred to Janice and Jambre
because what's done in the past is going
to be done again. But the truth will
always kill a lie. That's all I got.
>> Right.
>> Every time. Yes, sir. Thank you for
that. Hope that answered that question
as we continue to move on to our next
question.
>> Moving on. Shanquila Cool Joby says,
"Last week when I mentioned melon skin
tones, I was asking how can one
determine if they are Hebrew Israelites
considering there are so many
nationalities of color.
>> All right. So many nationalities of
color. How can one determine if they are
Hebrew Israelites? Yes. Carla.
>> Well, the whole thing is somebody wasn't
listening.
It wasn't determined by it, you know, it
wasn't determined by skin
[clears throat] color
or melatonin. It was determined by
condition that the Lord was going to
bring upon Israel.
The Lord told Israel,
"If you keep my laws and my statutes,
I'm going to bless everything you do.
You're going to be blessed in the city,
blessed in the field. The children going
to be blessed. Your stock going to be
blessed. Wherever you go, you're going
to be blessed. But if you don't keep my
commandments, you going to be cursed.
And once and told, you're going to be
cursed in the field. You going to do all
this. You're going to go into captivity.
You going to be sold as male and female
slave
and your children are going to be taken
away from and they going to go into
captivity. So you look for a people that
all this happened to just like it was in
in Deuteronomy the 28th chapter because
the Lord said it's going to be for a
sign.
So you look for what happened
uh whatever people this happened to this
curse come upon to give you let let's go
and show you what I'm talking about.
Let's go into Daniel the 7th chapter
and ninth chapter rather
I want you to read verses 11 and 12.
So this is how we determine who Israel
is. They got nothing to do with skin
tone.
No melon in the skin. It's got something
to do with who your daddy is.
>> So, uh, 9 chapter 9 verse 11 and 12.
Read it when you get there.
>> Yeah. All Israel have transgressed thy
law, even by departing, that they might
not obey thy voice. Therefore, the curse
is poured upon us in the oath that is
written in the law of Moses, the servant
of God.
Now if you go back and read the 28th
chapter to the Romney, the Lord tell you
everything that's going to happen to
Israel if they transgress his law. Now
we see we have transgresses law. But
keep reading. Pay attention to what the
book say.
>> And the oath that is written in the law
of Moses, the servant of God, because we
have sinned against him. And he have
confirmed his words which he spake
against us and against our judges that
judge us by bringing upon us a great
evil. For under the whole heaven have
not been done as have been done upon
Jerusalem.
Now he said look he have confirmed his
word the curse that he said he was going
to do to Israel and look what he said
for under the whole heaven. It has not
been done what is been done has been
done to Israel. We are a nation that was
scattered in all nations
and we went by ships and uh uh and and
other means and got stolen.
Now we don't have to go under the whole
heaven. Just look right here in America.
Who is it that came over here in the h
of the ship? Who is over here that was
sold as male and female slaves?
>> Whoever
>> the only one. Therefore, God said this
is a sign. So whoever came in this came
over in this entire hemisphere,
America's hemisphere and other places as
slave
and sold and the children's uh uh soul
and they hid away in prison houses and
all of these negatives, you'll find out
that we are the only one that's
happened. Let's think about it. It's the
American hemisphere. We are the only one
that came over here slave as slave.
Everybody else here that's here
migrated.
Everybody came here to enhance their own
well-being. We was brought over here
against our will to enhance somebody
else's well-being. Just like the Lord
said, it don't have nothing to do with
and we just it's just that we just
happen to be black. But being black
is not synonymous with synonymous with
Israel. All of the children of Ham is
black,
>> right?
>> But the children of Ham have not been
brought into slave in the hood of the
ships, stacked up like planks. They have
not been stood on blocks and uh uh uh uh
sold as male and female slave.
They have not had uh uh iron braces
around their neck
and breaded like cattle. We are the only
ones that this has happened to.
So you have Ham and you have us the same
color but we are different people and we
are Israelites. Why? Because the 28th
chapter Deuteronomy what other scripture
was telling you what's going to happen
to Israel and Israel only. That's why
that 12th verse say under the whole
heaven does not happen to anybody else
the way it happened to us. Read that
12th verse one more time.
And he have confirmed his words, which
he spake against us, and against our
judges that judge us, by bringing upon
us a great evil, but under the whole
heaven have not been done as have been
done upon Jerusalem.
But as it is written in the law of
Moses,
>> as it's written in the law of Moses,
28th chapter Deuteronomy 9,
find out who was brought here as slave
and sold and brought in in the bottom of
ships.
Then that's when you know who Israel is.
That how we know. It ain't got nothing
to do with skin color. We just happen to
be black. That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Well, hope that answers your question as
we move on to our next question.
Next one. Glenn Sirius asks, "Who is
this coming from the wilderness in Song
of Solomon 2 verse 6?"
>> All right. Who is this coming from the
wilderness in the Songs of Solomon? But
it's not two and six, but shed some
light, Brother Jerome.
>> Well, let's go read it. Um,
Songs of Solomon 2 and six. His
left hand is under my head and his right
hand doeth embraced me.
>> Okay, so you you probably actually meant
um chapter 3 and six. So let's go read
that.
Who is this that cometh out of the
wilderness like pillars of smoke,
perfumed with mirth and frankincense
with all powers powders of the merchant.
Yeah, that's talking about Israel. Uh it
the songs of Solomon is a love story
between
um Jesus who was the God of Israel and
his people, the children of Israel.
Okay. So, when you get to this third
chapter, can you read that um first
verse for me?
>> By night on my bed, I sought him whom my
soul loveth. I sought him, but I found
him not.
>> Yeah. So, Israel,
they sinned against God to the point
where the Lord
got away from him. Okay. And so they
Israel looking for the Lord, but they
can't find him. So they asked the
question, who is this that cometh out of
the wilderness? And that's that's
talking about Israel. Can we tie this to
let's tie this with uh the fifth chapter
and read verse six.
Go ahead. I opened to my beloved, but my
beloved had withdrawn himself and was
gone. My soul fell when he spake and I
sought him, but I could not find him. I
called him, but he gave me no answer.
>> Yeah. So Israel, they besought the Lord,
couldn't find them, and they they
perfume they up symbolically speaking to
present themselves before the Lord, you
know, with the myrr and everything like
it say in the uh fifth verse. Read that
fifth verse.
>> I rose up to open to my beloved and my
hands dropped with mirth and my fingers
were sweet smelling mirth upon the
handles of the lock. So he trying to
find the Lord and trying to make himself
self smell good. Israel tried to do that
and they look for the Lord and can't
find him, you know. And so that's Israel
that's in this wilderness. That sixth
verse of the third chapter. That's
that's all I got.
>> I want to throw something in.
>> Okay.
>> He said coming up out of the wilderness.
>> Coming up out of the wilderness, leaning
upon her beloved. Why coming out the
wilderness? Let's go to Ezekiel the 20th
chapter.
>> Okay.
and start reading at verse 30. We're
going to read a few verses.
>> This is the Lord talking to his people.
20 and 30.
>> Wherefore say unto the house of Israel,
thus sayeth the Lord God, are ye
polluted after the manner of your
fathers, and committed ye hoard them
after their abominations?
For when you offer your For when you
offer your gifts and you make your sons
to pass through the fire, you pollute
yourselves with all your idols, even
until this day. And shall I be inquired
of by you, oh house of Israel, as I
live, said the Lord God, I would not be
inquired of by you.
>> Go ahead. And that which cometh into
your mind shall not be at all that you
say, Will we be as the heathens, as the
families of the countries, to serve wood
and stone? But as I live, said the Lord
God, surely with a mighty hand and with
stretched out arm, and with fury poured
out, but I rule over you. And I will
bring you out from the people, and will
gather you out of the countries, wherein
ye are scattered, with a mighty hand,
and with the stretched out arm, and with
fury poured out. And I will bring you
into the wilderness of the people. And
there would I plead with you face to
face. Like as I pleaded with your
fathers in the wilderness of the land of
Egypt, so would I plead with you, sayeth
the Lord God.
Go ahead.
>> And I will cause you to pass under the
rod, and I will bring you into the barn
of the covenant, and I will purge out
from among you the rebels, and them that
transgress against me. I will bring them
forth out of the country where they
sjourn, and they shall not enter in the
land of Israel, and ye shall know that I
am the Lord."
>> So now, the Lord's going to take Israel
back to the wilderness, not to the land
directly, and he going to take him to
the wilderness, and he going to purge
out the rebels, and he going to deal
leave them dead in the wilderness. And
when he come up, he going to come up
with his beloved, which is Israel.
That's why he said he going to bring you
into the wilderness and he going to
bring you into the bond of the covenant.
He said in other places he going to
betro you unto him in the wilderness.
>> Right?
>> So as Israel's coming out to up out of
the wilderness after they have been in
there for three and a half years being
purged by Jesus.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question there as we continue to keep
moving.
Yes, keep moving. Linda Stringer says,
"I like to understand more about the
seven churches addressed by Jesus in
Revelation
chapters 1, 2, and three." What is the
significant of stars? The cities are all
situated in Turkey. Is Turkey Satan
seat?
All right, brother Julius share some
understanding on this question.
>> Let's go to Revelation the first chapter
and let's look at who these seven
churches are.
And this is uh the revelation um of
Jesus Christ that he had John write
about. Revelation one and pick it up at
verse four and we going to skip
when you get it. Verse four. John to the
seven churches which are in Asia. Grace
be unto you and peace from him which is
and which was and which is to come. And
from the seven spirits which are before
his throne.
>> Notice highlight the seven spirits which
are before his throne. Now skip down my
brother to verse 10. Look what John said
he was doing. Go ahead. I was in a
spirit on the Lord's day and heard
behind me a great voice as of a trumpet.
>> Yes.
>> Saying, I am Alpha and Omega, the first
and the last. And what thou seeest write
in the book, and send it unto the seven
churches which are in Asia,
>> which are in Asia, which are in Asia,
what we call modern day western Turkey.
Okay, this is to the new those New
Testament churches. uh had Paul that
Paul had visited, but they was in the
Roman province of Asia Minor. Go ahead.
Unto Ephesus
and unto Smina
and unto Pergamos and unto Thyra
and unto Sardis, and unto Philadelphia,
and unto Leadsia.
>> So those are your seven churches. Now,
each church had an angel assigned to it.
Okay? It had each one of them had an
angel assigned to it. Now skip down to
who what's another name for these
angels? Verse 20.
The mystery of the seven stars was thou
sawest in my right hand. And the seven
golden candlesticks. The seven stars are
the angels of the seven churches. And
the seven candlesticks which thou sawest
are the seven churches.
>> Now we can't read. We can't read the
chapters one, two, and three, but that's
how far the churches go. So now you want
to know the the uh significance of the
stars. The stars are the spirits or the
angels. Each one is sent to one of the
churches with a message. Okay. Now, uh
are they they all situated in Turkey?
But is Turkey Satan's seat? The answer
is no.
Let's go to Revelation chapter
uh to the church of uh Pergamus. There's
a message here
verse 12
uh 2 and 12.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And to the angel of the church in
Pergamum was right, these things said he
which hath the sharp sword with the two
edges.
>> Uhhuh. I know thy works and where thou
dwellest even where Satan seed
and thou holdest fastest my name and
hast not denied my faith
>> even those days wherein Antipus was my
faithful martyr who was slain among you
where Satan dwelleth
>> now where do Satan dwelleth or where
Satan see that let's go to Revelation
the 13th chapter
who
Revelation 13 and1. Go ahead and read.
>> And I stood upon the sand of the sea and
saw his beasts rise up out of the sea
having seven heads and 10 horns and upon
his horn 10 crowns and upon his head the
name of blasphemy.
>> Now we know through scripture and
through history that this is the modern
day EU the 10 n power nations of Western
Europe. Go ahead and read. And the beast
which I saw was like unto a leopard. And
his feet were as the feet of a bear, and
his mouth as the mouth of a lion. And
the dragon gave him his power.
>> And the dragon and the dragon, which is
Satan, the devil, going to get a
European Union, their power. They're
going to be working under the influence
of Satan. Go ahead.
>> And his seat and great authority.
>> So now that is what we call Rome. And
where? in Rome, the Vatican. That is
Satan's seat and that's where he working
from through the Catholic Church.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Brit Brett says,
"Unfortunately,
I work on the Sabbath days. I want to
make sure that I ask for the right day
to take off this year during the
Passover.
On the Sabbath day, we shouldn't work.
And Leviticus 23 verse7 is given.
>> All right, brother Jerome.
Well, um, this year the the Passover
actually going to fall on a a Wednesday,
uh, April the 1st at at sundown.
Uh so the s uh the Passover is actually
not a Sabbath, you know, but in the
future if the Passover should happen to
fall on the s the weekly Sabbath, you
you should take it off if you can so
that you can be off for the uh the
weekly Sabbath and keep the Passover if
you happen to fall on the weekly
Sabbath. Okay? But this year it's gonna
fall on a Wednesday, April 1st at at
sundown. Okay. Now um let's go look that
verse that you gave. Leviticus
23 verse 7.
You can read it when you get it.
>> And the first day he shall have a holy
convocation. He shall do no survile work
therein.
>> All right. Now in actuality that verse
is connected to uh the feast of unleven
bread on the 15th on the 15th day which
is the day after the Passover. So read
verse um five
for me. Go ahead.
>> In the 14th day of the first month that
evening is the Lord Passover.
>> Yeah. So that's on the 14th day. Okay.
Uh, and it's not a Sabbath. So, if you
happen to go to work on on the day of
the Passover this come when it fall on
Wednesday, that's that's okay. You can
still go to work. And, you know,
fortunately, hopefully, you can still
come to class. If not, then yeah, maybe
you should take off. If you happen to
work when the Sabbath um when the when
the uh Passover starts at at evening,
you know, you you might want to take off
so you can attend. Okay. But if you work
during the day, then you don't you you
can still go to work and just keep the
Passover when the evening come.
All right. That's all I got.
>> All right.
>> Yeah. He also
>> he wanted to know what days. He can also
call the office of the Israeli God and
have them mail him a list of the feast
days or you can go on the internet
>> download the feast days and then you can
give but
>> but if you get that letter insure it to
your boss and they'll give you the days
off that you need to take off.
>> Yeah. Thank you guys call.
>> All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Jean Shai asks, "Who was King
Neiel?"
>> Yes.
>> Who was King Lee Muel?
Also,
why did his mother advise him not to
drink wine or strong drink?
>> All right. Who was this king Limuel and
why was he advised not to drink wine or
strong drink? That's caller.
Well, if you read it to tell you why she
said don't do it because he going to
impair his judgment. But as far as this
king liel is concerned, I don't know who
he is. Maybe some one of you guys know
who he is. I don't.
All we looked at is Solomon's poetic
name.
>> Well, but you can't prove that, can you?
>> Let's see.
>> All right.
>> Is that correct?
>> Leave it alone.
>> Okay, we'll leave it right there as we
keep on moving to our next question.
>> Next one. This written says I need
clarification on the word breath
in John 20 verse 22.
And
when he had said this his breath on them
and said unto them, receive ye the Holy
Ghost.
The breath is the word of God.
I cross reference what Ezekiel 37
verse10.
Uh then is written says a customer came
to my window and said he was led to pray
for the patient and breathe on and
breathe or blew on him.
>> Yeah. So they got they got uh amb breath
or blue on him at the end but then
earlier they saying they breathe on
them. So brother Dre can you kind of put
that in order and shed some light
brother?
>> Yeah let's go to that John 20 and I want
you to pick it up at uh
verse 19. Brother Tanzel
go ahead when you get it. In the same
day at evening being the first day of
the week, when the doors were shut,
where the disciples were assembled for
fear of the Jews, came Jesus and stood
in the midst, and said unto them, "Peace
be unto you."
And when he had so said, he showed unto
them his hands and his side. Then were
the disciples glad when they saw the
Lord. Then said Jesus to them again,
"Peace be unto you. As my father hath
sent me, even so said I you." And when
he had said this, he breathed on them
and said [snorts] unto them, "Receive ye
the Holy Ghost."
>> Notice it said he breathed on them and
said, "Receive ye the Holy Ghost."
But he came in the room and he said,
"Peace be onto you and he said and it
said he said
he breathed on them and saith unto them,
receive ye the Holy Ghost." Let's go to
uh Psalm 33 and look at something there.
Psalm 33 and I want you to read verse
six when you get there.
Psalm 33 and verse 6.
>> By the word of the Lord were the heavens
made and all the host of them by the
breath of his mouth.
>> By the word of the Lord. So he spoke it
into existence.
And it says by the word of the Lord were
the heavens made and all the host of
them by the breath of his mouth.
So you talking when you talking you
breathing but somebody coming into a
place in in a restaurant and blowing
their breath on somebody that is
dramatics
>> has nothing to do with anything.
But he breathed on them. He spoke the
word and he said receive ye the Holy
Ghost. And he told them, "Whatever sins
you remit will be remitted."
And he went on from there and gave them
instructions on how they should walk.
That's all I got.
>> Um, can you cross reference? He gave
Ezekiel 37:10.
Yeah, that that Ezekiel 37:E10,
it talks about the winds coming on them
and it talks about that blowing on them.
So that is not equated to the word being
spoken in that way.
But if we we could go read it. Ezekiel
and 10. Read that when you get there,
brother.
>> For I prophesize as he commanded me, and
the breath came unto them, and they
lived, and stood up upon their feet, an
exceeding great army.
>> Okay, so this breath here, they lived.
It say, "So he prophesied as he
commanded and the breath came into them
and they live and stood upon their feet
and exceeding great army." What did he
breathe? What did he breathe? The breath
coming into them. Go ahead, read a
little bit more.
>> Then he said unto me, "Son of man, these
bones are the whole house of Israel.
Behold, they say our bones are dry
>> and our hope is lost, but we are cut off
for our parts.
>> And we dealt with that. We dealt with
that last week in the lesson, the dry
bones
uh dead in the valley and breath being
breathed into them and they lived. The
word was spoken onto them and they
lived.
Let me can I throw in a couple of
things?
>> Sure.
>> Just a couple of verses so we get away
from this bookery.
First thing is let's go in uh uh uh St.
John 6 read 63 verse 63
66 and 68.
>> Yes sir.
>> It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profitth nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are spirit and they
are life.
>> So, so that's this Holy Spirit that you
know you know that breath that they
breathe on them. Why is the skip down
and read 66 and to 68?
>> From that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with them.
Then said Jesus unto the twel, "Would
you also go away?" Then Simon Peter
answered him, "Well, Lord, to whom shall
we go? Thou has the words of eternal
life."
>> That man is word, he told his spirit.
Now I want to show you something that
the uh uh uh Ethiopian said to Phillips.
Let's go into Acts the 8th chapter,
read 26 [clears throat]
27. Then we're going to skip down and
read 30 and 31.
>> And the angel of the Lord spake unto
Philip, saying, "Arise, and go toward
the south, unto the way that goeth down
from Jerusalem, unto Gather, which is
desert." And he arose and went, and
behold, a man of Ethiopia and unit of
great authority under Candace, queen of
the Ethiopians, who had the charge of
all her treasures, and had come to
Jerusalem for to worship.
Verse 30,
>> and Philip ran thither thither to him,
and heard him read the prophet Isaiah,
and said, Understand thou what thou
readest? And he said, "How can I except
some man should guide me?" And he and he
desired fiddle that he would come up and
sit with them.
>> That's it. That's it. He said, "Do you
understand what you're reading?" He
said, "How can I unless some man guide
me?"
>> Yes, sir.
>> In other words, I don't understand
unless somebody teach me. So that
breathing that Jesus did on there,
that's as simple as saying that he
taught them.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Exactly. Thank you, guest call. Uhhuh.
All right, hope that answered your
question and we're going to keep on
moving to our next one.
>> Next one. Way too much salt warrants
explanation on Genesis 3 verse 15.
>> Genesis 3. Let's go there. Tanzil
Genesis 3
and 15.
And we'll ask the guest caller once you
read it, share some light on there. 3
and 15.
>> Genesis 3 and15.
And I will put enmity between thee and
the woman, and between thy seed and her
seeds, and it shall bruise thy head, and
thou shall bruise his heel.
>> Now, okay. the woman
uh uh uh we're going to show that this
woman is talking about not talking about
Eve. It's talking about Israel. And
it's going to be enimity between
Israel, the woman's seed, and Jesus,
I mean, and Satan. Now, let me show you
what I'm talking about. Let's go quickly
to Revelation the 12th chapter.
I want you to read verse one. And then
we going to jump out of there and uh uh
uh go to uh Exodus the uh uh uh 37th
chapter. We going to come back. Okay.
Revelation 12 and 1.
>> And there appeared a great wonder in
heaven, a woman clothed with the sun and
the moon under her feet, and upon her
head a crown of 12 stars.
Okay. So, this is this woman. How do we
identify that this is Israel? You can
keep your a space there cuz a marker
there cuz we're going to come back.
Let's go into uh Genesis the 37th
chapter
and we going to read verse 1 through3
and we're going to skip down and read
verses 9 and 10.
And Jacob dwelt in the land wherein his
father was a stranger in the land of
Canaan. But these are the generations of
Jacob. Joseph being 17 years old was
feeding the flock with his brethren. And
the lad was with the son of Bha and with
the sons of Zeopa, his father wives. And
Joseph brought unto his father their
evil report. Now Israel loved Joseph
more than all his children, because he
was a son of his old age. And he made
him a coat of many colors. [snorts] Now
we're talking about Joseph here. What
verse was that?
>> That was the end of three.
>> Okay. So this is Joseph. And Joseph was
a dreamer of dreams. Skip down to verse
9. Read 9 and 10. And he dreamed yet
another dream, and told it to his
brethren, and said, "Behold, I have
dreamed a dream more, and behold, the
sun
and the moon and the 11 stars made
obesience to me."
>> Now, we look at, we saw that in the
Revelation the 12th chapter, didn't we?
>> Right?
>> Woman clothed in the sun and the moon
under her feet, she had 12 stars. He
said 11 stars here made obedience
obedience to me. So what did Jacob say
to Joseph?
>> And he told and he told it to his father
and to his brethren. And his father
rebuked him and said unto him, what is
this dream that thou has dreamed? Shall
I and thy mother and thy brethren indeed
come to bow down thyself to thee to the
earth?
See now, now Jacob recognized that that
dream was talking about him and uh him
which he hid the son and his wife which
is the moon and the 11 stars which
Joseph's 11 brothers if you add Joseph
to it is 12 stars.
So this woman when you go now this woman
is talking about Israel. I want to make
sure that you understood this. Now,
let's go back to Revelation and we're
going to start at verse one again and we
going to read the uh uh
and we're going to read from 1 to 5. Go
ahead.
>> And there appeared a great wonder in
heaven, a woman clothed with the sun and
the moon under her feet and under her
head a crown of 12 stars. And she being
with child cry travailing in birth and
pain to be delivered. And there appeared
another wonder in heaven. And behold, a
great red dragon, having seven heads,
and 10 horns, and seven crowns upon his
head. And his tail drew the third part
of the stars of heaven, and did cast
them to the earth. And the dragon stood
before the woman, which was ready to be
delivered, for to devour her child as
soon as it was born.
and she brought forth a man child who
was to rule all nations.
>> So now the dragon stood before the woman
which is Israel to devour her child as
soon as he was born.
That mean that he's the woman's seed.
Isn't that correct?
>> And what happened uh uh when a child was
born? Read that verse again.
and she brought forth a manchild
who was to rule all nations with the rod
of iron and her child was caught up unto
God and to his throne.
So that man child was talking Jesus.
Now read Psalms 110 and 1.
The Lord said unto my Lord, sit thou at
my right hand until I make thy enemies
thy foottool.
And he's talking about sit at my at his
right hand in heaven. So now the woman
seed
is Jesus. There going to always be
enmity between Jesus and Satan.
>> Now they crucified Jesus, which he had
to do, but Jesus was raised from the
dead. So that mean he bruised his heel.
But Jesus going to bruise Satan head.
How's he going to do that? By throwing
him in the lake of fire.
Okay.
>> Yep.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on
with the time check.
>> Yes. The time is 8:17. Uh, Linda
Stringer asks, "Is the gathering of the
Israelites in Deuteronomy 30
the same as coming of Jesus in 1
Thessalonians 4:17?"
Is Jesus coming to the earth twice?
>> All right. Look like they need some
light on that Deuteronomy 30 and 1
Thessalonians 4:17. Let's go that
Deuteronomy 31st. Tanzel
and the guest scholar shed some light
from there.
>> Deuteronomy 30.
>> Yeah, I don't know where they want to
pick it up at 30. Guess caller.
>> Well, start at verse one.
And it shall come to pass when all these
things are come upon thee, the blessing
and the curse which I have set before
thee, and thou shalt call them to mind
among all the nations, whether the Lord
thy God have driven thee, and shall
return unto the Lord thy God, and thou
shalt obey his voice, according to all
that I command thee this day, thou and
thy children with all thy heart, and
with all thy soul, that then the Lord
thy God will turn thy captivity, and
have compassion upon thee, and will
return, and gather thee from all the
nations, whether the Lord thy God have
scattered thee, if any of thy be out.
>> Now that hooks it up, that hooks it up
with Thessalonians, 1 Thessalonians 4
chapter. The Lord thy God will return
and gather thee. That mean he got to
come,
>> right? Well, let's go and read uh uh
Thessalonians
>> 4 and 17.
>> Yeah, go read it cuz this is the same
time. Go ahead, get read it when you get
there.
>> Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air, and
so shall we ever be with the Lord.
Bless the coming of the Lord. go to
Matthews 24
and read verse 27 and we're going to
skip down and read verse 29 and 31
because when the Lord heaven ruled back
and the Lord start coming at first
Thessalon the 4th chapter
that's when he going to also that's the
be that's that's the beginning when he
get he's going to uh return Israel
27 and skip down and read verse 29 31
>> For as the lightning cometh out of the
east, and shineth even into unto the
west, so shall also the coming of the
son of man be. Immediately after the
tribulation of those days shall the sun
be darkened, and the moon shall not give
her light, and the stars shall fall from
heaven, and the powers of the heavens
shall be shaken. And then shall appear
the sign of the Son of man in heaven.
And then shall all the tribes of the
earth mourn, and they shall see the Son
of Man coming in the clouds of heaven
with power and great glory.
And he shall send his angels with a
great sound of a trumpet, and they shall
gather together, his elect, from the
four winds from one end of heaven to the
other.
So now that's at that's at the same time
that it is with first Thessalonian the
4th chapter. Now the thing about it is
is he going to come to the earth?
Let's see where he was the last time he
was uh on earth. Let's go into Acts the
first chapter read verse 6 through 12.
And when they therefore was come
together, they asked of him, saying,
Lord, would thou at this time restore
again the kingdom to Israel?
And he said unto them, it is not for you
to know the time or the season which the
Father hath put in his own power.
But ye shall receive power after that
the Holy Ghost has come upon you. And
you shall be witnesses unto me both in
Jerusalem and in all Judea and in
Samaria and unto the utmost part of the
earth. And when he had spoken these
things, while they beheld, he was taken
up, and the cloud received him out of
their sight. And while they looked
steadfastly towards heaven, as he went
up, behold, two men stood by them with
white apparel, which also said, "Ye men
of Galilee, why stand ye gazing up into
heaven? This same Jesus, which is taken
up from you unto heaven, shall so come
like manner, as ye have seen him go unto
heaven."
Then return they unto Jerusalem from the
mount called Olive, which is from
Jerusalem, a Sabbath day journey.
>> So okay, when Jesus left this earth, the
last place his feet touched was on the
Mount of Olives. And them two men, which
is angels, said that when you see Jesus
going up, he gonna come back in like
manner. And they left from the Mount of
Olives. So let's see where his feet
going to hit when they come. Zechariah
14th chapter verse 1-4
>> Behold the day of the Lord cometh and
thy spoil shall be divided in the midst
of thee. I will gather all nations
against Jerusalem to battle and the city
shall be taken and the houses rifled and
the women ravished and half of the city
shall go forth into captivity and the
residue of the people shall not be cut
off from the city. Then shall the Lord
go forth and fight against those
nations, as when he fall in the day of
battle, and his feet shall stand in that
day upon the Mount of Olive, which is
before Jerusalem on the east. And the
Mount of Olive shall cleave in the midst
thereof toward the east, and toward the
west, and there shall be a very great
valley, and half of the mountain shall
remove toward the north, and half of the
toward the south.
And ye shall flee into the valley of the
mountains, for the valley of the
mountain shall reach unto Asel.
Yeah, ye shall flee like as ye fled from
before the earthquake in the days of
Uzziah, king of Judah, and the Lord my
God shall come and all the saints with
thee.
>> So now let you know when Jesus started
descent, he is not going to stop until
he hit this earth. So the mount of
olives is on this earth. Right.
>> But I want to give one other
confirmation. Let's go into Job chapter
19.
We're going to read verse one.
Then we're going to skip down and read
verse 23- 27.
>> All right. Job 19
>> verse one. Then Job answered and said,
"How long will you vex my soul and break
me in pieces with words?"
>> Now he's talking. Skip down to verse 23
and read to 27.
>> Oh that my words were now written. Oh
that they were printed in the book that
they were graven with the iron pen and
lead in the rocks forever. For I know
that my redeemer liveth, and that he
shall stand at the latter day upon the
earth. And though after my skin worms
destroy this body, but yet in my flesh
shall I see God, whom I shall see for
myself, and my eyes shall behold and not
another, though my reigns be consumed
within me.
So to let you know that when he hit this
when Jesus come he is coming back to the
earth. He left the earth from mount of
olive. When he came back come back his
feet going to hit mount of olive
>> and all the people in the first
resurrection that was raised and changed
going to come with him. Those are the
saints and like Job said I notice my
redeemer live it. I'm going to see and
in the latter and I'm going and and then
I'm going to see it and I'm and in the
latter days he going to stand up on the
earth. So yeah, he coming back to earth
and he ain't leaving after that. That's
all I have to say.
>> All right.
All right. Way too much sauce. We hope
that that answered your question as we
continue to move on.
>> Uh moving on. And that was from uh Linda
Stringer. So now we have Valencia.
Valencia wants you to explain Ezekiel 20
47 and 48.
>> All right. Ezekiel 20 47 and 48. Correct
Deborah. That was Linda Stranger. Thank
you for that. Uh, brother Julius
um
um the whole 20th chapter of Ezekiel is
a historical review of Israel's um
idolatry and they uh rebelled against
the Lord from the time that they came
out of Egypt all the way into the Egypt.
They rebelled in Egypt and and then they
got to the Canaan land and rebelled. So,
it's also about the recovery of Israel
and um what the Lord how he going to
gather his people. Let's read that verse
uh pick it up at verse uh
45. Ezekiel 20 and 45.
Moreover, the word of the Lord came unto
me, saying, Son of man, set thy face
toward the south, and drop that word
toward the south, and prophesied against
the forests of the south field.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And say to the forests of the south,
hear the word of the Lord. Thus sayeth
the Lord God, Behold, I will kindle a
fire in thee, and it shall devour every
green tree in thee, and every dry tree.
The flaming flame shall not be quenched,
and all faces from the south to the
north shall be burnt therein, and all
flesh shall see the eye of the Lord have
kindled it, and it shall not be
quenched.
>> I'm going to do you, Jerusalem, Judah.
I'mma do you. Can't nobody help you. You
gonna know it's from the Lord. That's
all I got. Guest caller.
>> That's what it says.
>> All right, we're going to leave it right
there and we're going to keep on moving.
>> Yes. Skyrider wants you to explain First
Corinthians 5 verse 5. How can one be
delivered unto Satan to destruction, but
then say that the spirit of may be
saved?
Let's go to first Corinthians 5 and5.
And when you get there, Tanzel, go
ahead. Guest caller, take it from there.
to deliver such a one unto Satan
>> to deliver such a one unto Satan for the
destruction of the flesh that the spirit
may be saved in the day of the Lord
Jesus.
>> Now, let's show you somebody that was
delivered to Satan who's headed in this
particular case. Let's go to Job the 2
chapter and read verse 6.
Yo, two
and six.
And the Lord said unto Satan, Behold, he
is in thy hand, but save his life.
Now there,
>> did you read the whole six?
>> Yeah.
That's all I want you to read right
there. He delivered Satan uh uh uh uh
Job into the hand of Satan, but he tell
him but he said don't kill it. Now let's
go into First Timothy
first chapter
and read verse 18 to 20.
1 Timothy
1 and 20
>> 18-20.
>> Okay.
This charge I commit unto thee, son
Timothy, according to the prophecy which
went before on thee, that thou by them
might as war a good warfare,
holding faith and a good conscience,
with some having concerning faith have
made shipwreck
of whom?
>> Hello.
>> Yeah,
>> this first
>> Timothy.
Yeah.
>> The verse
verse 18 to 20. The first chapter
>> verse 18 and 20.
>> Yeah. First Timothy
>> one. Pick it up at that 18 and uh then
skip down to 20.
>> No, I wanted to read
>> 18, 19, and 20. Right.
It's 1 Timothy 1 and8, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Which start of discharge.
>> Yep. That's it.
>> Okay. That's what I was reading.
>> Try it again.
>> Okay.
Let me make sure that's the right place.
Hold on a second.
Let's see. Uh
>> cuz verse 20 speaks about being
delivered under Satan.
>> Yeah. Well, read for 18 to 20 then.
This charge I commit unto thee, son
Timothy, according to the prophecy which
went before on thee, that thou by them
may as war good warfare,
holding faith in a good conscience,
which some having put away concerning
faith, have made shipwreck, of whom is
Himus
and Alexander, whom I have delivered
unto Satan, that they may learn not to
blasphe me.
>> So now, so he said he delivered them to
Satan just like God delivered the uh Job
to Satan. But that's for a reason. Now
let's go into Hebrews the 12th chapter
and we going to read verses 4-7.
Ye have not resisted under blood stri
striving against sin, and ye have
forgotten the exhortation which speaketh
unto you as unto children. But my son,
despise not thou the chastity of the
Lord, nor a faint thou are rebuked of
him. For whom the Lord loveth he
chastenth, and scourge every son who he
received.
If you endure chastening, God dealeth
with you as with sons. For what son is
he whom the father chastises not. But if
you be without chastisement,
whereof all are partakers, then are ye
pastors and not sons.
>> Now listen to what what he said there.
God scourages all those that he love.
He chastis you only get chastised when
you are doing wrong.
>> Right. Okay. And so what to do is the
Lord put some drama in your life when
you start sinning against him. So you
will rethink it and stop sinning.
So what happened is he is hurting his
flesh and blood. But he going to save
you from the lake of fire. That's what
all Paul is saying.
But living to Satan. You know the flesh
going to be destroyed.
>> That don't mean he going to destroy you
and kill you like that. He's going to
punish you, chastise you. And Satan is
the one that the Lord used to chastise
people.
>> Right?
>> But like he said to Job, don't kill him.
>> Same thing here.
So if Lord love you and you do something
wrong, he going to do you just like your
father do you. Going to whoop your butt.
>> That's right. to save you from
eventually getting thrown and doing
something stupid and end up in jail or
in the graveyard.
Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Danielle Wellington asks, "If
you work for someone in their home and
you notice they have an earn, does that
mean you're you're uh you are unclean
because you are in their home? If so,
what do you do about it?"
>> Well, um if they got earn in their
house, every time you go in there, you
unclean day after day after day. But
however, what you can do is when you
leave their house, go home, take your
shower. But if you touch that earn, it's
seven days. So you're only unclean until
the evening if you go in and don't touch
the earn. But let's go into Numbers 19.
Numbers 19
and pick it up, brother. I'm going to
read that verse. Uh read verse one and
then we going to skip down to 14.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses and unto
Aaron saying.
>> So this the Lord speaking here about how
he want this thing done. Verse 14.
>> This is the law. When a man dieth in the
tent, all that come into the tent and
all that is in the tent shall be unclean
seven days. So, we just want to read
that, too, because we know we have a a
lot of new people that tune in all the
time. But if someone dies in that tent,
all they come into that tent, all that
are in that tent shall be unclean for
seven days. And if you touch a dead
body, you unclean for seven days. Skip
down to 16.
And whosoever toucheth one that is slain
with a sword in the open field or a dead
body or a bone of a man or a grave shall
be unclean seven days.
>> Even an earn shall be unclean seven
days. Skip down to 22.
>> And whosoever the unclean person
toucheth shall be unclean. And the soul
that toucheth it shall be unclean until
evening.
>> Yep. So anytime you go into that house
where they have that urn, yes, you are
unclean.
So all you can do is if the conversation
ever presents itself where you might be
able to shed the word and shed some
light on them about the urn, then you
can take that opportunity to do so. But
yeah, you unclean every time you go in
that house where the urn is at. And
that's all I got.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next one.
>> Moving on. Charles Tumer says, "I had a
cousin that just died and my mother had
a dream of her falling in a black hole,
reaching up asking for help because they
they are trying to hurt her. Should we
take dreams serious?"
All right, we talking about death,
dreams, and taking them serious. Brother
Dre, what you say?
>> First of all, I just want to say
condolences to you and your family for
the loss of your cousin.
>> And secondly, I want to go to the
scripture about dreams. Let's go to
Ecclesiastics 5 and we're gonna read
verse three.
>> Ecclesiastics 5 and three. Read that
when you get there, brother.
Read. Yes.
>> For a dream cometh through the multitude
of business and a fool's voice is known
by multitude of words.
>> Yeah. So a dream comes through the
multitude of things. Like you know it's
common to hear about falling into a a a
pole or into a space where you just keep
falling within a dream. But biblically
speaking, let's see what happens to a
person when they pass. Let's go over to
Ecclesiastics 9 now. Ecclesiastics 9 and
five and six. Ecclesiastes 95 and 6.
Read that when you get there, brother.
>> But the living know that they shall die,
but the dead know not anything. Mhm.
>> Neither have they anymore reward, for
the memory of them is forgotten.
>> Mhm.
>> Also their love and their hatred and
their envy is now perished. Neither have
there any more portion forever in
anything that is done under the sun. So
they won't be coming to you
calling for help and screaming
and asking you to, you know,
help them to get out of a hole that they
fallen in. That's that's tormenting.
Uh so let's go over to one other place.
Let's go over to now. Let's go to uh Job
Job 14
and read 12 and 13, brother. 12, 13, and
14. Read that and that'll be it.
>> So man lith down and riseth not till the
heavens be no more. They shall not awake
nor be raised out of their sleep.
Oh, that thou wouldest hide me in the
grave, that thou would have keep me
secret until thy wrath be passed, that
thou wouldest appoint me a set time, and
remember me. If a man die, shall he live
again.
All the days of my appointed time will I
wait until my change come.
and thou shalt call and I will answer
thee and thou will have a desire to the
work of thy hands.
>> So this is that when the Lord call the
dead is going to be raised and the
living will be changed but
>> when when you die you go to the grave
>> right
>> you will be there until the coming of
the Lord or until the right throne
judgment. You
>> know that that's a dream,
>> you know. And another place in Jeremiah
say, "Him that have a dream, let him
tell a dream, but him that have my word,
let him speak my word faithfully."
>> Word that.
>> Why don't you go and read that? Jeremiah
23rd
25.
>> Yes, sir.
TW
23 and 25. Brother,
>> I have heard what the prophet said that
prophesies lies in my name, saying, I
have dreamed. I have dreamed. How long
shall this be in the heart of the
prophets that prophesies lies? Yet they
are prophets of the deceit of their own
heart, which think to cause my people to
forget my name by their dreams. But they
tell every man to his neighbor, as their
fathers have forgotten my name. For
Bael, the prophet that have a dream, let
him tell a dream. And he that have my
word, let him speak my word faithfully.
But what is the child to the wheat? Say
the Lord.
Now, I let you know if you have a dream,
tell a dream. But then that don't that
don't mean that you trying to get a
message.
>> You want to get a message, read the word
of God.
>> That's it.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Oh, yeah. All right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Hope that answers your question. Sister
Deborah, time is a ticking.
>> Uh, yes. Uh Skyriter asks, "How do you
know that the word lasciviousness
means causing others to sin when the
dictionary and other preachers says it's
intense lustful behaviors?"
>> Brother Julius,
>> you answered the question with the last
uh with the last part of that uh intense
lustful behavior. Lasciviousness is a
behavior and it's a social behavior.
Why? Because just like bad behavior is
contagious, can make can make other
people do bad things, so can good
behavior. Now, lascivious is lewd
behavior. LWD uh it covers a lot of
things, especially sexual behaviors.
It's a work of the flesh. Let me show
you what I'm talking about. Let's go to
Galatians chapter 5.
See, what man say don't mean too much of
nothing. What God say means everything.
Galatians 5
uh 10 and pick it up at verse 16.
>> But this I say then, walk in the spirit
and ye shall not fulfill the lust of the
flesh.
>> Notice what you said in your question.
Lustful behavior. Skip down to verse 19
and let's look at these behaviors. Go
ahead.
>> Now the works of the flesh are
manifested, which are these: adultery,
fornication,
uncleanness, and lasciviousness.
>> All of this can cause other people to
sin. Go ahead.
Idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance,
emulation, wrath, strife, seditions,
heresies, envy,
murderers, drunkenness, rebelling, and
such like as of the which I tell you
before, as I have also told you in time
past. Yes.
>> But they which do such things should not
inherit the kingdom of God.
>> And the book is clear. Every man going
to be judged according to his works.
Includes the servants. When you cause
others to sin, adultery can cause others
to sin. Just like a chronic smoker can
somebody pick it up, they're going to
adapt that same behavior. Same thing as
drunkenness. But that's what this is. It
is it is social behavior. Social
behavior. So that's how it can cause
others to sin.
M
>> and then you can it goes even further.
You could do it can become digital. You
like sending nude pictures
and designed to incite others to for to
get a reaction.
So that's how the serious can cause
others to sin.
>> Okay.
>> That's all I got.
>> That's right. Yeah. We live in the
spirit. Let us also walk in the spirit.
Right, brother?
>> And you will not fulfill the lust of the
flesh. That's it. All right. Hope that
answered your question. Time check on
our next one.
>> Uh, yes. The time is 8:46.
Yseph asks, "Why is the tribe of Dan not
mentioned in Revelation 7?" Manessa is
the tribe of Joseph.
>> Why is Dan not mentioned in Revelation
7? Brother Julius,
>> he is mentioned. It It's not mentioned
by name, but he's there. I'mma show you
that he's there. Uh let's get right to
the uh right to the the point of this
right here. Re uh Revelation 7
and let's look at uh what the message is
at verse three.
>> Saying hurt not the earth neither the
sea nor the trees till we have sealed
the servants of our God and therefore he
is.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And I heard the number of them which
were sealed.
>> Now let's pay attention to what we're
about to read. Go ahead. And there were
sealed 144,000s
of all the tribes of the children of
Israel.
>> Of what? Tazil?
>> Of all the tribes of the children of
Israel.
>> That means that Dan cannot be left out.
So where you see Manasseh, it should be
as a typo. It should say Dan. I'mma show
you what I'm talking about. Let's go to
Genesis chapter 35.
>> I believe that's what I want.
So dad is there because he is one of the
children of Israel. Genesis 35 and pick
it up at verse 23. Genesis 35 and 23.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
>> The sons of Leah, Reuben, Jacob's
firstborn, and Simeon, and Levi, and
Judah, and Issachar, and Zebulon,
the sons of Rachel, Joseph, and
Benjamin.
And the sons of Bha, Rachel's handmmaid,
Dan and Napali.
>> There's Dan. You don't see Manasse
there, do you? Keep reading.
>> And the sons of Zeopar, Leah's handmade,
God, and Asher. These are the sons of
Jacob, which were born unto him and
Padamaran.
>> Now, we have a saying in Israel of God,
throw out all of what ain't, and what's
left is what is. Why is Dan mentioned
here but not in revelation 7? Because
it's a typographical era error. Joseph's
son is Ephim and Manasseh. But Joseph is
also mentioned there. So Manasseh should
not be there. It should be replaced with
Dan. That's all I got.
>> All right. Good light there as we
continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Edward Bobber asks, "Are the
Mexicans and Indian people in the Bible?
If so, where?" Mexicans and Indians, are
they in the Bible, Jerome?
>> Yeah, but they they mentioned by way of
the sons of Noah.
Okay. And they fall out of one under one
of the three sons. Okay. But um yeah,
the Mexicans are Gentiles according to
the Bible. They're Europeans, you know,
and more likely they they they uh come
come through. They they Spanish.
>> Okay. But let's go to uh Genesis 10
and let's pick it up at verse one. lead
to the five.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> Now these are the generations of the
sons of Noah, Shem, Hel, and And
unto them were sons born after the
flood,
the sons of Japhat, Goomemer and Magog,
and Madi, and Javan, and Tubal and Mach
and Tyrus. and the son of Goomemer,
Ashenaz, and Ripath and Togamar, and the
sons of Javan, Alishia, and Tarses,
Kendum, and Dudenim. By these were the
aisles of the Gentiles, divided in their
land, everyone after his tongue, after
their families, and their nations.
>> Okay? So, they fall under the Gentiles.
That's who they are. Uh they not
Hammites because the the the Hammites
they come out of Ham and we call them
Africans today. All right. So they not
Africans. They don't come out of Shim
either. They come out of JFAT. Right.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that. As we
keep on moving
>> moving on. Little fingers asked why did
the Colossians wear the star of David?
Is this biblical?
>> Why did the Colossians wear the star
David? Let's call them.
>> Well, the first thing is the only reason
for them to do that
is that either they are dealing with the
pagan star, the star of Rimra and Moak.
But in this case, I think they was
wearing it because they was exposed to
the so-called Jews, Edom, because David
and the Jews, so-called Jews, so they
study only the first five books of
Moses. And David, which is the Torah,
and David is not in the Torah.
So the only reason I see them wearing
that star is because they got exposed to
the so-called Jews and they think that
they should do that
>> which is wrong. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we continue to move on.
>> Yes. J Will of God asks, "Is praying
silently okay or is there a specific way
you must pray?"
Well, praying silent is okay. And is
there a specific way you must pray? Um,
when you go and one of the ways the Lord
say you can enter into your closet just
you and him and your prayer to him. Hey,
that's between you and him. So there's a
variety of ways that you can pray. But
let's go into that uh Luke the 11th
chapter and we'll just give you a couple
of examples here. But the best way to
send up your prayers is when you're
serving God. That is the best way to
make sure that you don't get a busy
signal.
All right. Luke 11. And let's pick it up
at that verse one. Luke 11 and 1. Cuz it
after Jesus got through praying, one of
his disciples asked him say, "Hey, teach
us how we should pray." Go ahead,
brother.
And it came to pass that as he was
praying in a certain place, when he
ceased, one of his disciples said unto
him, "Lord, teach us to pray as John
also taught his disciples."
And he said unto them, "But when ye
pray, say, Our Father, which are in
heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done, as it as
in heaven, so in earth.
Give us day by day our daily bread, and
forgive us of our sins as we also
forgive everyone that is in debt to us,
and lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil." So this is one
way that the Lord was saying, you know,
that you can pray. And also at the close
of the program, uh, brother Tanzel is
going to show us another way to pray
when he closes out with the Lord's
Prayer. But let's go into Psalms 55
because you asked about praying in
silence. Psalms 55 and let's pick it up
and let's read that verse 16 and 17.
Psalm 55:16
and 17.
Go ahead, brother.
>> Ask for me that will call upon God, and
the Lord shall save me.
Even in morning, and at noon will I pray
and cry aloud, and he shall hear my
voice.
>> So, you know, there's a lot of different
ways you can pray. Evening, morning, and
noon. But, uh, tell you one thing, Lord
say, pray without ceasing because this
world is in bad shape. But, there's a
variety of ways to pray. So, there's a
couple right there, but that's all I
got.
All right, we're going to keep it moving
because time is a ticking and we'd like
to get these two more questions in for
sure. Sister Deborah, what's the next
one?
>> The next one Jay Will of God also asks,
"Is Esau
if if Esau is Jacob's brother, then does
that make him a Hebrew as well? All
right, brother Dre. Look like we need
some explanation on that. If
>> Yeah, he is Jacob's brother and
biologically he is Isaac's son and
Abraham
uh grandson.
>> So, you know, when you let's go to
Genesis 25,
Genesis 25 and 23.
Let's look at something here real quick.
Read it when you get there, brother.
>> And the Lord said unto her, "Two nations
are in thy womb, and two manner of
peoples shall be separated from thy
bows, and the one people shall be
stronger than the other people, and the
elder shall serve the younger."
>> And so, Edom, Esau is the father of the
You could read that in Genesis
36 8-9.
And in Genesis 14 and 13, you can read
that Abraham, Abram the Hebrew, and Esau
is Abraham's grand grandson.
So yes, you could look at him as the as
a Hebrew, but at the end of the day, we
just read that two nations are in thy
womb and two man of people will be
separated from thy bows.
>> That's all I got.
>> Hebrew Edomite.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question. Next one, Sister
Deborah.
>> Yes. Sandra Allen asks, "Are there any
pagan connections to Thanksgiving? I've
been hearing a lot of negative things
about it, and I want to know if I should
totally cancel it."
>> All right,
>> that's called a popular question indeed.
Thanksgiving,
>> ain't nothing written in the Bible to
condemn it or promote it.
All right. Sound like sound like the
choice is yours.
All right, Sister Deborah. Let's go into
another question as we walk into new
territory.
>> Yes. We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, February the 25th, 2026.
Kylie Parker asks, "Are we supposed to
start getting rid of all the bread by
Passover or by the first day of the
feast of unleavened bread? Are we
supposed to stop eating leaven bread by
Passover?"
>> All right, guest caller, would you like
to have first crack at that question
there?
>> Yes, we are.
Because you're going to take the
Passover with unleaven bread.
>> So you don't go back to deal with
unleaven bread once you take the
Passover.
>> So you get it all out of your house. Get
it all out of your house before the sun
go down on the 14th day of the month.
Abel.
>> Yep.
All right. And for our newcomers, that's
not putting it in your garage or in the
trunk of your car. Gotta be totally off
of your premises.
[laughter]
>> All right.
>> Give it and you can't give it to anybody
else because you're causing them to sin.
>> That's right. Yep. Can't give it to no
one else either. So, let's do what thus
says the Lord. All right, Sister
Deborah. Next one. Miss White uh asks in
Matthew 6 verse1 17 on the day of
atonement when we fast do we anoint our
head and if so with what
>> all right Matthew 6:17
and uh she wants to know about anointing
your head when you are fasting so let's
go and read that Tanzel and then let's
open it
to the panel. Uh, pick it up, brother,
at that verse 16. Read 16 and 17.
Moreover, when ye fast, be not as the
hypocrites of a sad countenance, for
they disfigure their faces, that they
may appear unto men to fast. But verily,
I say unto you, they have their reward.
But thou when thou fastest, anoint thy
head and wash thy face.
>> All right. So it looks like the question
that point was about anoint thine head.
>> And if and if so with what?
>> Listen, that is not talking about
anointing like getting anointed. What
it's saying is look, if you going to
fast, you get up and what do we have?
Don't we have to put grease in our hair
and fix everything? Fix oursel up.
>> Yeah.
>> Got to shower. Clean yourself up.
>> That's it. And comb your hair. Don't be
walking around, you don't put no don't
don't put no grease in your head, you
know, like we have to put grease and oil
in our head because we got this hair.
Don't be walking around with a long face
and looking like you suffering. simply
saying, "Fix yourself up
>> because that fast ain't between you
>> and the people. It's between you and
God."
>> Look like to them that you ain't you
ain't doing nothing. You ain't fasting.
Ain't got nothing to do with nothing in
your head.
>> All this anoint that man is just putting
oil and stuff on your head. You know,
like what you usually do,
>> right? Look at the kind of hair we have.
Don't you have to put something on it?
Some grease or something on it?
>> Otherwise, be dry.
>> Otherwise, it' be like we used to be in
the old days when you had naturals and
no no grease in it.
>> About anointing like you would anoint a
person that's sick,
>> right?
>> All it's saying is fix yourself up.
Don't look like a scarecrow.
>> Right. All right. So, Sister Deborah,
we're going to ask for another time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 9:02.
>> Oh, we have ran out of time. And we'd
like to thank everybody from all around
the world who tuned in with us, even all
our newcomers who are joining us also.
And we'd like to say that if you
submitted a question and we didn't get
to it, please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah, take it and put it in rotation
and we will address that question next
week. And so also before we close out
once again we would like to say please
join us for part four of our black
history the priest of God. You don't
want to miss out on that great lesson
there. So brother Tanzel on that note
please close us out as everybody be safe
be blessed and stay prayed up. Go ahead
my brother. Our Father, which art in
heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread, and forgive us of our debts
as we forgive our debt to us, and lead
us not into temptation, but deliver us
from evil. For thine is the kingdom, and
the power, and the glory forever. In
Jesus' name we pray. Amen.